Inventory of the Jin Wensi papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Jin Wensi papers
1932-1952
68042
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Transcripts of conversations with foreign officials, memoranda, and reports relating to Chinese foreign relations with the Netherlands, Belgium, Norway, Poland, and Czechoslovakia; the Sino-Japanese War; and the Korean National Council to the League of Nations, 1919.
Jin, Wensi, 1892-1968.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1968.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Chinese diplomat; ambassador to the Netherlands, 1933-1944; ambassador to Norway, 1945-1950. Referred to as both Jin Wensi and Wensi Jin.
Scope and Content of Collection
Transcripts of conversations with foreign officials, memoranda, and reports relating to Chinese foreign relations with the Netherlands, Belgium, Norway, Poland, and Czechoslovakia; the Sino-Japanese War; and the Korean National Council to the League of Nations, 1919.
The original order of the files has been mostly maintained, except for Interviews, which have been arranged chronologically. Folder titles have been transcribed as they appeared on the original files.
Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Governments in exile.; China--Foreign relations--Netherlands.; China--Foreign relations--Norway.; Korea--History--Independence movement, 1919.; Netherlands--Foreign relations--China.; Norway--Foreign relations--China.; Diplomats--China.
- Interviews, 1932-1952 (Box-folder 1: 1-6, 2: 1)
- The Latest Phase of the Sino-Japanese Crisis, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Maps of the Netherlands, 1935-1936, undated (Box-folder 2: 3)
- Letter on Japan's Annexation of Korea, undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Letter to the Minister of Foreign Affairs, 1933 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Arms and War Material Prohibition Memorandum, 1935 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Processing and Printing Problems Report, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Germany and Dutch War Report First Manuscript, 1939 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Sino-Dutch New Treaty Draft, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Exit Leopold III: The Abdication of King Leopold III of Belgium, 1952 (Box-folder 2: 10-12)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains a manuscript, compact discs, and a printed copy of a monograph written by Jin Wensi on the abdication of King Leopold III. The original manuscript was finished in 1952, and additional copies were made posthumously in 2007. Includes a photo of King Leopold III's abdication.